<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>jackxalan</title>
        <link>https://jackcummings.me/</link>
        <description>Jack's Blog</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <atom:link href="https://jackcummings.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<item>
<title>(Update) My Disney Career</title>
<pubDate>Fri, 3 May 2024 12:05:84 -0400</pubDate>
<guid>https://jackcummings.me/blog/update-my-disney-career.html</guid>
<link>https://jackcummings.me/blog/update-my-disney-career.html</link>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>
<description>
    <![CDATA[
<p> In trying to make my “career” posts a bit more lively and to add some fun breaks to my “resume” page, I thought I would include some pictures where I can of my different gigs over the years. While these are nowhere near my favorite pictures, these moments can help illustrate some of the wildest days I had on tour.<br><br>

<img src=“https://jackcummings.me/images/ro-tour-guide-video.png” alt="Me, leading a VIP Tour down Main Street">
<p class=“caption”>From <a href=“”>Rosanna Pansino’s video</a> of her trip to Disneyland with some friends; the highs and lows she captured pretty well make up what it’s like to be on tour.</p>

<img src=“https://jackcummings.me/images/walts-apt-tour.jpg” alt="A posed photo of me inside Walt’s Apartment">
<p class=“caption”>It’s well known amongst Disneyland’s fans that Walt Disney had an apartment on Main Street; we got to share it with folks everyday on a Guided Tour. Getting to see folks visit a place that meant this much to them is an honor I won’t soon forget.</p>

<img src=“https://jackcummings.me/images/tros-blue-carpet” alt="Me at The Rise of Skywalker premiere">
<p class=“caption”>While this wasn’t the <strong>most</strong> surreal Star Wars experience I would have that year… (thank you, Galaxy’s Edge’s Opening Ceremony) It was still pretty incredible.</p>

While it’s so fun to reminisce, I can’t overstate how homesick going through old tour photos makes me. Every beloved friend I see in pictures is a gut punch, every mentor and mentee an uppercut to the jaw. I miss these folks terribly, and it tears me up that I don’t know when I’ll see all of them next.<br><br>

If you’re reading this, love y’all. Miss you. I still mean every word I wrote in my <a href=“../blog/one-last-tour.html”>goodbye tour</a>
]]>
</description>
</item>    		
<item>    
 						<title>My Disney Career</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid>https://jackcummings.me/blog/my-disney-career.html</guid>
            <link>https://jackcummings.me/blog/my-disney-career.html</link>
            <dc:creator>Jack Cummings</dc:creator>
            <description>
								<![CDATA[ <p>
		My "career" began with three sessions of the <a href="https://jobs.disneycareers.com/job/orlando/disney-college-program/391/60316939040">Disney College Program</a>, beginning in <strong>2013</strong> as a frontline <strong>Attractions Cast Member</strong> in Disney California Adventure at Mater's Junkyard Jamboree. That fall, I moved to Florida for my second College Program as an Attractions CM at Dumbo the Flying Elephant and The Barnstormer Featuring the Great Goofini. In <strong>2014</strong>, I moved back to California as an Attractions CM at Golden Zephyr, Jumpin' Jellyfish, and Goofy's Sky School.<br><small>(It remains a point of pride that, to my knowledge, I am the only person to operate planes at both of Goofy's esteemed aviation attractions.)</small><br><br>
The "Keys to the Kingdom Tour" at Magic Kingdom played a significant role in my desire to work in the parks; as such, my eye was always on the Guided Tours program that Guest Relations operates. So, in <strong>November 2014</strong>, I switched gears and joined <strong>Disneyland's Guest Relations</strong> department.<br><br>
As a <strong>Guest Relations Host</strong>, I began my journey up the "customer service" ladder. While our most obvious functions were attending to concerns and providing service recovery, upgrading and downgrading tickets, and facilitating services for guests with disabilities; I quickly found my niche at our Guest Information Locations. At those remote information kiosks within the parks, we were responsible for <em>any piece of information about the resort you could think of</em>: restaurants' menus, attractions' height requirements, locations of every restroom across the >100 acre Resort, you name it. The next year, that information became my bread and butter as I got a bit of a promotion to <strong>Guest Relations Trainer</strong> in <strong>September 2015</strong>, a role I held for almost two years. My training sessions were tours in and of themselves, teaching my trainees about every. single. location at the Disneyland Resort.<br><br>
Finally, in <strong>May 2015</strong>, I became a <strong>Disneyland Tour Guide</strong>. Over the course of 4.5 years, I would lead the majority of tours our program offered: Welcome to the Disneyland Resort, Holiday Time at the Disneyland Resort*, Disney California Story, Frozen - Live at the Hyperion: Behind the Scenes**, Disney's Happiest Haunts**, Walk in Walt's Disneyland Footsteps*, Walt's Apartment Tour*, tours of the Dream Suite, and a very special addition - The Grand Circle Tour**. The tours lasted from ~2 to 3.5 hours, and each most had a dedicated script which was to be delivered as-close-as-possible to verbatim.<br><br>
In June 2016, I took on a larger role as a <strong>Guided Tours Lead</strong and would subseuently become a <strong>Guided Tours Trainer</strong> (see: tours above with *) that holiday season. This era would see some of my proudest career achievements, as I also developed (both collaboratively and as lead developer, from script segments to entire tour concepts) some incredible tours with some incredible people (see: tours above with **). Wildly, I also was able to use my amateur design skills to design assets for the tours!<br><br>
<img style="width: 40%" src="images\gct-credential.png">
<p class="caption">The GCT credential was modeled after Disneyland's old <a href="https://d23.com/a-to-z/ticket-books/">ticket books</a>, produced by Globe Ticket.</p>
The two tours that will be forever closest to my heart are The Grand Circle Tour (GCT) (formerly; currently known as The Disneyland Railroad Tour) and Disney's Happiest Haunts (Haunts). For GCT, some dear friends and I developed a love letter to the Disneyland Railroad and I got the chance to wax poetic (too much, tbh) about steam power and the magic of physics and engineering.<br><br> For Haunts, I was tasked with rebuilding the tour from the ground up. Though it was admittedly a little silly and a bit clumsy for a framing device, I was thrilled to create an audio experience where the tour met Snow White's Magic Mirror and was beset by "spirits" all across the parks.<small>(I will forever be bonded with Snow White's Magic Mirror because of this.)</small>
<img style="width: 40%;" src="images\2017-haunts-credential.png">
<p class="caption">Approval from Walt Disney Imagineering for this credential remains a point of pride I will take to my grave.</p>
While I was hestitant to jump in at first, in <strong>September 2016</strong> I took on yet another role, this time as a <strong><em>VIP</em> Tour Guide</strong>. These tours offered a chance for a Tour Guide to join your family or party as your own, private concierge to Disneyland for the day. As a VIP Tour Guide, I got to meet people and take part in experiences the likes of which I would have never dreamed as a kid. I used to call it my "astronaut job" - one you can't necessarily do forever, but is one of the greatest gigs on earth if you can snag it. <small>(I was literally paid to ride rollercoasters.)</small> As with seemingly every other position within Guest Relations, I became a <em>VIP Trainer</em> in <strong>October 2018</strong>. Training new guides was  *also* incredibly unique, including teaching <em>dining ettiquette</em>(!?) in one of Disneyland's most exclusive spaces, Club 33.<br><br>
With VIP Tours, I would truly live the life some could only dream of: I walked the <em>blue</em> carpet at a Hollywood premiere; I said hello to some of the most famous people on the planet, and joined more than a few for a day at Disneyland; and I experienced a day that I could have not even dreamed for myself as a child supporting the opening of Star Wars: Galaxy's Edge. With Guided Tours, I got to share my passion for the creative arts and innovative engineering that I maintain <em>prove</em> that theme parks are forms of art in and of themselves. And in my last role, as a Land of Dreams guide, I was able to put it all together in a once-in-a-lifetime behind-the-scenes experience (that grew from a germ of an idea which, in part, originated in Frozen: Live at the Hyperion - Behind the Scenes, which I helped develop) where we would whisk families to attractions as if they were celebrities, while being able to <em>show</em> and share the stories of art an innovation it was harder to demonstrate "onstage." <br><br>
It was truly like walking... once upon a dream.<br><br>
But, like with all dreams, it would end. The COVID-19 pandemic closed the parks for a year and made many of us re-think our futures. My future included a little dude who I would want to be home with instead of guiding multiple 10+ hour tours each week. So, in 2021, about a month after being called back to Disneyland, I said goodbye to Walt's Magic Kingdom.<br><br>
<small>I think about it every day. It's likely I will never hold another job I enjoy as much.</small> 🎠
<hr>
Next time... the <a href="https://academymuseum.org"> Academy Museum of Motion Pictures</a>.
								</p>]]>
						</description>
	</item>
				<item>
            <title>Noodling, Tinkering, and Doodling</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
            <guid>https://jackcummings.me/blog/noodling.html</guid>
            <link>https://jackcummings.me/blog/noodling.html</link>
            <dc:creator>Jack Cummings</dc:creator>
            <description>
            <![CDATA[  <p>
                I really like to noodle. Often, I'll have a random idea for a project with no real thought or intent behind why or where it should live, and yet… I noodle.<br><br>

                While this has been true of various projects of mine since high school, the noodling generally falls into two buckets: "art" and "web".

                <hr>

                <h2>Doodling</h2>

                In high school, I elected to skip Art class. Instead, I filled my time with band (an art) and television production (which also revolves around the arts). Obviously, I wasn't disinterested in the arts as a whole, as so much of my time was spent engaging and creating it; however, the traditional skills valued in a high school art class weren't taught in a way I could easily grapple week-to-week. As such, I can't say I ever <em>really</em> learned to draw, sculpt, etc.<br><br>

                When I got to college, after switching majors (from Archeology to Experience Design), I landed in even more "non-traditional" spaces in which to create art. I took a few theater classes, a digital art class, and some experimental classes that allowed me to really dig into installations that intrigued me, the kinds you might find in a... theme park, for instance. These classes are where I finally started to feel my own skills develop.<br><br>

                While I have never felt comfortable enough with those skills to put "artist" on a business card; the urge to sketch, to create, to learn and improve has never left me. Normally, these "doodles" are just random ideas I work out in Sketch and throw onto <a href ="https://instagram.com/indiana_jack">social media</a>. But now, those ideas can have a <a href="projects.html">home</a>!<br><br>

                <img src="https://jackcummings.me/images/skate-font.png">
                <p class="caption">My wife, Ashley, has been a figure skater since childhood; looking at the blade of her skate one day, I had a random idea for a workmark/typeface that was pretty easy to implement.</p><br>
                <img src="https://jackcummings.me/images/pokemon-bug-merit-badge.png">
                <p class="caption">I spent many hours as a youngster in Scouts, eventually becoming an Eagle Scout. I probably spent as many (or more) hours playing Pokemon. This fake Scouting Merit Badge book was born of those two experiences.</p>

                <hr>

                <h2>Tinkering</h2>
                Back to high school - the other major, defining force which reared its head in the late aughts was the rise of social media. Facebook, mySpace, and Twitter all really took off during my high school years, and this profoundly shaped my interests for the coming decade and a half.<br><br>

                On mySpace, as any millennial will excitedly tell you, we learned what an "a href" was. A basic understanding of HTML allowed you to <em>express yourself</em> with profile themes, art, etc. On Twitter, I found scores of tech reporters and artists that introduced me to the art behind many of my favorite tech products, which resulted in a newfound love of Apple's industrial design and Google's quirky, colorful interfaces. This fascination would result in a blog, which I ran for 4-5 years way back when, integrating Twitter and Tumblr as much as I could: POW Blogs.<br><br>

                <img src="http://jackcummings.me/images\powbanner.png">
                <p class="caption">One of the various logos/banners for POW Blogs, with which I lovingly referred to one of my favorite creative institutions of all time, a little gaming company based in Kyoto.</p>

                Twitter, along with (amazingly) POW Blogs, resulted in some really fun online connections through a community of fans of my then-favorite band, Family Force 5. As @jackozord, I was <em>constantly</em> engaging with band members, fans, and even... the band's PR rep? It was truly one of my favorite eras of the scene and the internet.<br>

                A decade (and what seems like a lifetime) later, I would jump into what has been one of my most fulfilling creative endeavours to date: PROJECT: DEXTER, where I learned how to build an iOS app with Swift to realize a childhood dream: Ash's Pokedex from the 90's Pokemon anime.<br> <small>But that's a story for a different time.</small>

                <img src="https://jackcummings.me/images/dexter-kadabra.png"><br>
                <p class="caption">A screenshot from PROJECT: DEXTER.</p>
                
                <hr>

                Nowadays, all of those endeavours have landed in this: a website of my own that allows me to doodle, to tinker... to just generally <strong><em>noodle</em></strong>.<br><br>
                If I had a point here, I suppose it's this:<br>
                <blockquote>Don't let intimidating hobbies like art or engineering scare you from toying around with them. Creative and artistic expression come in many forms, and as long as the endeavor is <em>for you</em>, the resulting works will be fulfilling.<br><br>Create for yourself and no one else.</blockquote>
                <hr>
                I would be remiss to end without pointing to <a href="https://lmnt.me">LMNT</a>, a blog written by an artist I discovered way back... in high school. Louie has designed for the <a href="https://lmnt.me/intro/portfolio/shanghai-disneyland.html">Disney Parks</a> and <a href="https://lmnt.me/intro/portfolio/apple.html">Apple</a>, along with every notable <a href="https://lmnt.me/blog/wallpapers/">desktop wallpaper</a> that's been ripped off for the last decade. He posted about <a href="https://lmnt.me/blog/tinkering.html">"Tinkering"</a> in 2016, and much of this site comes from a principle he outlined in that post:
                
                <blockquote>"You start with something that exists and you change it to understand it."</blockquote> 
                
                Louie has kickstarted my interest in the <a href="https://lmnt.me/blog/craft-internet.html">Craft Internet</a>; a space where we may create and communicate no other motives than creation and communication, influence and engagement be damned. Join us. &#128128;]]>
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>An Identity for Anaheim</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid>https://jackcummings.me/blog/an-identity-for-anaheim.html</guid>
            <link>https://jackcummings.me/blog/an-identity-for-anaheim.html</link>
            <dc:creator>Jack Cummings</dc:creator>
            <description>
            <![CDATA[ <p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vexillology">Vexillology</a>, or the study of flag design, seems to have taken the internet by storm over the last decade, and has become a serious hobbyist interest. In every corner of the US, it seems like we&#8217;ve heard of a recent flag redesign. From <a href="http://www.mdah.ms.gov/taxonomy/term/131">Mississippi</a> to <a href="https://flag.utah.gov/">Utah</a> to <a href="https://www.sos.state.mn.us/about-the-office/news-room/sec-simon-s-statement-on-state-flag/">Minnesota</a>, states are leaving behind some dated, problematic icons of the past to embrace this new wave of interest in design.</p>
            <p>This &#8220;new wave&#8221; of flag design is primarily based upon guidelines identified by the North American Vexillological Association publication <a href="https://nava.org/good-flag-bad-flag">Good Flag, Bad Flag</a>. The &#8220;Five Principles&#8221; outlined in that publication are:</p>
            <ol>
            <li>Keep It Simple</li>
            <li>Use Meaningful Symbolism</li>
            <li>Use 2 or 3 Basic Colors</li>
            <li>No Lettering or Seals</li>
            <li>Be Destinctive or Be Related</li>
            </ol>
            <p>While these rules do tend to mesh with iconic flag designs, the contemporary flags being designed to fit exclusively within these principles have more recently been receiving critiques of their own.</p>
            <iframe class="yt-embd" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/kRtUiORUh7c?si=KkEXmtqnXmQmVahk" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
            <hr />
            <p>A few years back, the city of Anaheim, California was hoping to do the same. At the time, they had what some considered to possibly be the <strong>worst</strong> flag design <em>ever</em>.</p>
            <img src="/images/old-anaheim-flag.svg.png" alt="" />
            <p>The original designer, Howard &#8220;Bud&#8221; Nagel, was the Public Information Officer for Anaheim in the 60s. As such, artistry and thoughtful composition didn&#8217;t seem to be a priority.</p>
            <p>In 2018, the city sought designs from artists to re-think its flag; I threw my hat in!</p>
            <p>At the time, I had been living in Anaheim for 4&#8211;5 years; it had really become my home-away-from home. Outside of Disneyland, I truly loved spending time downtown on Center St. Promenade, which had been drastically reimagined in the five years prior. Local business had taken over, with everything from a comic book store (RIP Pop!) to a traditional Japanese bakery.git-</p>
            <p>The real draw for non-locals, though, was the <a href="https://www.anaheimpackingdistrict.com/">Anaheim Packing District</a>, one of the earliest food halls to become successful in SoCal. It opened in 2014 in the shell of the former Sunkist citrus packing house, a reminder that before fairy tales and mice arrived in Anaheim, citrus farming defined the region. Stories of the orange groves are plentiful in discussions of Disneyland&#8217;s past; and while it may not be the seat of Orange County, Anaheim is probably the most well-known metropolis for anyone not familiar.</p>
            <p>This line of thinking, then, brought me to an obvious conclusion and design inspiration. For my design, I used a similar &#8220;silhouette&#8221;, if you will, to the old design - two bars above and below a central image. For the image itself, I tried to play with the concept of an orange that would <em>read</em> as an orange while still fitting within the principles outlined above. (Admittedly, I was enamored with those five principles then, an attitude I don&#8217;t necessarily still keep.)</p>
            <img src="/images/anaheim-flag.png" alt="" />
            <p>While there would be things I would do differently today (retain more detail in the orange like Mississippi&#8217;s flower opposed to attempting a Canada-esque silhouette), I still really enjoy this design! It&#8217;s one of my favorite pieces of design-work over the years, and perhaps my favorite flag I&#8217;ve done.</p>
            <hr />
            <p>Ultimately, though, I wouldn&#8217;t be chosen. The winning design is more reminiscent of flags like Washington, D.C.&#8217;s or Chicago&#8217;s - too much, in my opinion.</p>
            <img src="/images/alternate-anaheim-flag.png" alt="" />
            <p>I wish there was a bit more spirit in the design, and perhaps city officials thought so too, as Anaheim chose to revert back to its original in 2019. For all that effort, the &#8220;new&#8221; flag lasted less than a year.</p>]]>
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Attempted Photgraphy</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid>https://jackcummings.me/blog/attempted-photography.html</guid>
            <link>https://jackcummings.me/blog/attempted-photography.html</link>
            <dc:creator>Jack Cummings</dc:creator>
            <description>  
            <![CDATA[ <p class="p1"><span class="s1">I’ve always liked taking pictures.</span></p>
            <p class="p1"><span class="s1">When I was a kid, I
                would enter ten photos every summer to be judged
                in our local 4-H fair. I never won a big prize or
                advanced to the State Fair, but I enjoyed it and
                kept going. Looking back now, I think my photos
                and their grades are pretty telling of how I have
                approached photography over the years.</span></p>
            <p class="p1"><span class="s1">When I was a kid, I
                think I believed that photos needed to be of
                something impressive, that the goal of a photo
                was
                to communicate that I, the photographer, had been
                somewhere or done something interesting. The
                photo
                was more or less “look where I have been.”</span>
            </p>
            <img
                src="https://jackcummings.me/images/btmrr.jpg">
            <p class="caption">Wow! Look! I caught
                a
                train coming through at Big Thunder Mountain
                Railroad! (Walt Disney World)</p>
            <p class="p1"><span class="s1">I remember being
                impressed with myself for taking a photo at a
                Cincinnati Reds game, catching the ball in
                mid-flight as it raced from the pitcher toward
                home. The shot itself was wide, as it was taken
                from the stands and we didn’t have a particularly
                large lens with which to zoom, and the colors
                were
                only tinted by the film we used (probably the
                cheapest cache on the wall in Wal-Mart). This, to
                me, was peak photography - I had been somewhere
                fun and had caught an impressive sight with the
                camera.</span></p>
            <p class="p1"><span class="s1">In college, this
                would shift slightly.</span></p>
            <iframe class="yt-embd" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/H-QEAHgYc6g?si=v-ID-4bownh7fXZb" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
            <p class="p1"><span class="s1">In 2009, I met a
                girl
                I would marry eight years later, and she got me
                into this band called The Wonder Years. In 2011,
                they would release a single called Local Man
                Ruins
                Everything in advance of the album Suburbia, I’ve
                Given You All and Now I’m Nothing. The album
                would
                be a love letter of sorts to smaller residences
                in
                the Midwest; while the lyrics paint a very clear
                picture of the Philadelphia suburbs, small towns
                in the Midwest have similar vibes and it was easy
                to apply the narrative to a little place in
                Indiana. The record would be promoted with
                pictures and videos shot in South Philly, in
                areas
                highlighting its mundaneness.</span></p>
            <p class="p1"><span class="s1">This perspective
                caught my attention - here was photography
                focused
                on the anthesis of what I believed made a good
                photo, and it could be done in my backyard! When
                Instagram arrived the same year, my eye
                completely
                changed. Now, I was looking for mundane magic -
                moments that were so normal to me that, in
                retrospect, revealed a certain beauty.</span></p>
            <img
                src="https://jackcummings.me/images/instatrain.JPG">
            <p class="caption">My first image on
                Instagram in 2011</p>
            <p class="p1"><span class="s1">Over the years, I
                would waffle between shooting subjects fairly
                clinically, showcasing only the subject itself
                with no supporting elements, to delving back into
                this interest in artistic interpretations of the
                mundane, composing an image of the everyday to
                capture its beauty.</span></p>
            <p class="p1"><span class="s1">I suppose this
                fanciful flight between interests was best
                captured on my <a href="https://iamcalledjack.tumblr.com">Tumblr</a>, where I would scour the
                tags across the platform compiling images that
                suited my mood in the moment.</span></p>
            <p class="p1"><span class="s1">The biggest obstacle
                in my journey towards better photos is, looking
                back, perhaps unintuitive; I spent so much time
                at
                Disney Parks, where so much is perfectly
                photogenic and colorful on its own. I never
                needed to think “outside the box” to capture a
                moment, instead being able to capture picture
                perfect subject at anytime. (See BTMRR above as
                an example.)</span></p>
            <p class="p1"><span class="s1">Still, there was
                always an itch to improve, to capture moments, to
                improve my compositional eye.</span></p>
            <img
                src="https://jackcummings.me/images/birdsandtwain.jpeg">
            <p class="caption">While not a perfect photo, I
                return to this often because of the moment - the
                feeling and sight of seeing so many birds fly
                perfectly overhead.</p>
            <p class="p1"><span class="s1">Recently, I’ve tried
                to begin learning how to break out of my normal
                mode of taking &amp; editing photos, thanks to
                some guidance from “Photography YouTube.”There,
                creators share (for free!) tips that could easily
                be curated into a class, making ”studying” easy
                and fun.</span></p>
            <iframe class="yt-embd" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/FFQwMvb20Ck?si=GOtR2n8ujmdBv4Y0" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
            <p class="caption">Downloading Halide
                to shoot and editing using Darkroom per Stalman’s
                advice is where my journey truly started over the
                last year.</p>
            <iframe class="yt-embd" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/m2OTMIRyiFo?si=ZbTUvVhb_nxORIc6" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
            <p class="caption">I really love
                James’s relaxed style of presentation, and this
                composition video (along with his more recent
                “Exposure Myth” video) has really helped me to
                start thinking differently about how I want to
                shoot intentionally.</p>
            <img
                src="https://jackcummings.me/images/joshuatree.jpg">
            <p class="caption">An old photo from
                Joshua Tree I edited recently to try to
                incorporate some of the lessons I learned from
                the videos above</p>
            <p class="p1"><span class="s1">In the coming year,
                I hope to really turn photography into a hobby. I
                miss running around Disneyland, taking pictures
                of sights big and small that caught my eye.
                What’s to say I can’t do the same with the
                seemingly infinite charm found in the smallest
                pockets of New England?</span></p>
            <p class="p1"><span class="s1">Until then, keep
                learning. Go find your spark.</span></p>
            <img
                src="https://jackcummings.me/images/dinosaurpark.jpeg">
            <p class="caption">If I had to choose a
                favorite picture I’d ever taken, it might be this
                one. Thanks to some new editing tricks, I now love it even more.</p>]]>
            </description>
        </item>
<item>
<title>One Last Tour</title>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 April 2021 12:05:11 -0400</pubDate>
<guid>https://jackcummings.me/blog/one-last-tour.html</guid>
<link>https://jackcummings.me/blog/one-last-tour.html</link>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>
<description>
    <![CDATA[
  <p>
    <img src="https://jackcummings.me/images/tour-guide-crest.png" style="max-width: 150px">
    <br><h2 class="onelasttour">One Last Tour</h2>
    <p class="addressee">April 12, 2021<br><br>
        Tour Guides & Guest Relations Cast Members<br>
        Town Square, Main Street, U.S.A.<br>
        Disneyland</p><br>
    <h3>Guided Tours Garden</h3>
    Good morning, everyone! My name is Jack and and I’d like to invite you to join me for one final Guided Tour. I will be your guide one last time as I share how you and this magical place have truly changed my life forever.<br><br>
One of the countless things that makes this place so unique is how it continues to imbue in all of us the traits that forged our favorite storyteller (and our very first tour guide) Walt Disney. Disneyland is a place of inspiration, of limitless potential; it allows us to explore our world and our most inner selves, and to share in dreams that we look forward to realizing in the most terrific future… But more than this, I think there is a more important truth: as we adventure toward endless frontiers dreaming of the future, we do so <strong>together.</strong> 
<br><br>So now, together, let us take one final walk through Walt Disney’s Magic Kingdom, Disneyland U.S.A.<br><br>
    <h3>Town Square</h3>
    <blockquote class="onelasttour">“To all who come to this happy place, welcome.”</blockquote>
    With these words on July 17, 1955, Walt Disney changed the world. While the decades since that day haven’t been perfect and society has been beset by trials and tribulations, Main Street, U.S.A. has stood as a message and an ideal: regardless of origin, here at Disneyland, you are welcome. From that very first day, Main Street has been a reflection of what I believe Walt may have seen as his interpretation of the American dream. In his own way, he gave us a place where <em>“huddled masses yearning to breathe free”</em> might free themselves from their troubles, even if for a day or just a moment. 
<br><br>As we know, that first day wasn’t freedom from trouble for Disneyland or for Walt. The street that surrounds us became an allegory for what many feared might happen: just as guests’ high heels were sinking into the pavement, so too was the prospect of Disneyland’s success. The media was quick to write off Walt’s dream as naïve and unobtainable; but, as we know, hope is the foundation of persistence and Walt Disney was of the most hopeful of his time.
<br><br>In our time at Disneyland, we have all known triumph and failure. We’ve seen the best of what humankind has to offer, and we’ve had days that question our faith in the dream, and our hope for the future. So I invite you now, as we continue on to the heart of Disneyland, to free yourself of your troubles and doubts, even if for just a moment. Think of where you are, think of the millions that have been here before, and remember: no matter what, <strong><em>this is a happy place and here you are welcome.</em></strong><br><br>
    <h3>Central Plaza</h3>
    Welcome to the heart of Disneyland, the Central Plaza. As we know, the Central Plaza exists as a conjunction of Disneyland’s arteries: the paths and portals from which all of our Magic Kingdom’s ideals become real. Walt’s idea for this “Hub” sprung from fatigue: as he visited museums and other public places, he tired of returning to the same place again and again just to move forward. For Disneyland, he dreamt of a place for guests to center themselves - a place where they might never be lost and where it was always easy to find their north star. (You know, the second one to the right.)
    <br><br>I find it fitting that alongside Sleeping Beauty Castle, a star of of sorts - a compass - resides near the center of Disneyland, always pointing north… and surrounding it, lyrics with which we are all intimately familiar:
<blockquote>“When you wish upon a star, your dreams come true.”</blockquote>
We all know that line from the 1940 classic Pinocchio, where Jiminy Cricket serves as Pinocchio’s north star: his conscience. Pinocchio learned rather quickly that doing the right thing was often the more difficult decision. Again and again Jiminy would offer his advice, returning to principles he knew would lead Pinocchio back home, so that he might not lose his way. It may have been tiresome to hear, but in the end… Pinocchio learned what it meant to be a “real person”: <strong>you make mistakes, you grow from them, and you allow that experience to shape your moral compass, ever pointing towards your own north star.</strong><br><br>
    <h3>"it's a small world"</h3>
    In 1955, Disneyland introduced America to some of Walt Disney’s most closely-held beliefs, hopes, and dreams. Less than a decade later, Walt would endeavor to introduce those ideals to the world. In 1964, WED Enterprises (a private firm owned wholly by Walt himself) opened four unique attractions for the New York World’s Fair: the Carousel of Progress, Ford’s Magic Skyway, Great Moments with Mr. Lincoln, and of course… “it’s a small world”.  Nearing what would be the end of his time with us, Walt wanted to give back what he had been given. Disneyland had been inspired by the “real world” from the beginning; and now, Disneyland would inspire the “real world.” Two of the park’s founding beliefs would be reflected in the attractions developed for the Fair: progress and unity. The idea that a “theme park ride” could <em>“foster a better understanding among nations of the world”</em> was revolutionary and continues to be relevant today and important for tomorrow.
    <br><br>Now, in my final moments as a denizen of the “Happiest Place on Earth”, as I leave these realms of <em>“yesterday, tomorrow and fantasy”</em> for that “real world,” I hope to take with me my greatest inspiration from this magical place: you. 
    <br><br>Six years ago, you welcomed me with open arms, and invited me to join a truly special family, clad in a tartan I will proudly wear (in other forms) for decades. From you, I learned the powers of empathy, passion, and confidence. You pushed me to be better, and supported me when I failed. You all have been my compass, my north star, and I hope I’ve done right by you along the way and made you proud. <strong>Thank you for everything.</strong>
    <br><br>I had a dream, and without you all it would have been just a start.
    <br>Thank you for guiding me to follow it with mind and heart.
    <br>Thank you for allowing my dream to become a reality.

    <br><br>It’s been a dream come true and an honor to be a Disneyland Tour Guide; and as always…

    <br><br><strong><em>“It’s been my pleasure.”</em></strong> Thank you all so much. I love you and I’ll miss you.




    <br><br><br><br><strong>Tour Guide Jack</strong><br><br>
]]>
</description>
</item>
    </channel>
</rss>